Lok Acharya

Columbus, OH | (614)886-1922 | lokacharya774@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/LokAcharya | Link to Personal Portfolio

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I have worked as a supply Chain Operation Manager in shipping company Sheldy Cargo, I work as a line lead in FedEx, and currently serving in the Ohio Army National Guard as a Team leader. I am a current student of We Can Code It (Bootcamp) as a Full-Stack Java Software Developer

TECHNICAL INVENTORY

Java • Spring • Thymeleaf • JavaScript • MVC • HTML • CSS • TDD • Agile (Scrum) • Object Oriented Programming (OOP) • JSON • React • REST APIs • Responsive Design / Mobile • Relational Databases • Source Control / GitHub

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE/PROJECTS

[Personal Github address here]

We Can Code IT, Cleveland, OH Software Development Student, 2021

Planned, designed, and developed professionally programmed applications in collaborative team-based and independent settings, demonstrating the proficiency to earn Software Development Certificate.

Virtual Pet Shelter: Designed console application that lets users create and interact with their own virtual pets. Java, Visual Studio, Git, Github, GitBash, TDD, OOP

Workout Builder: Designed console application that lets users build and customize personal workout.

Java, Visual Studio, Git, Github, GitBash, TDD, OOP

Arrays and Loops: Utilized knowledge of C# to solve various puzzles with array and loop methods.

Java, Visual Studio, Git, Github, GitBash

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (WORK HISTORY)

Ohio Army National Guard, Cleveland, Ohio (May, 2017 to current)

Soldier/Team Leader

- Train soldiers
- Work with team to execute missions
- Keeping accountability of the soldiers on the team

Sheldy Cargo, New York, NY (June, 2021 to December, 2021)

Supply Chain Operation Manager

- Maintain accurate records of items shipped and received.
- Verify and keep records on incoming and outgoing shipments and prepare items for shipment;
- Prepare records of merchandise shipped;

FedEx, Lockbourne, Ohio (December, 2021 to March, 2022)

Line Lead

- Lead a team of 10 to 20 packers to accomplish a daily goal
- Train new team member
- Communicate with supervisor and maintenance to insure a productive shift

EDUCATION & TRAINING

We Can Code IT

Certificate of Software Development, 2021

Columbus Downtown High School Career Center

Certificate of Manufacturing Engineering